Welcome once again to my channel Bond
Finance where I tell you
how to increase your savings and where to
save money, that is, if some other
person, suppose, is saving one lakh rupees in 12 years and is
dividing 12 lakhs into 16 lakhs and
you are not able to save even 12 and a half lakhs of 12 lakhs in 12 years, then I will
save you from making this mistake
and also tell you the ways to convert 16 lakhs into 20 lakhs, 25 lakhs, so
welcome, let me come to what we are going to talk about in this video,
I have taken
this State Bank's fake exam, why is it a
business, the agency people must have taken it, they must be
knowing that there is only one paper
for any agency and whichever agency you want to
take, you choose it in advance, so then a
question comes in the mind
that like this is a government bank, this is a government company,
so you take LIC only,
why don't you take State Bank, okay, for this, for a
little 2 minutes I
want to tell you about LIC and what was its beginning, right
That happened in Europe, okay, it
happened in Europe, but the main work of insurance is to
make policies for the customer, that is, to
make such policies for the customer where he gets
maximum benefit - the goal is the
customer's retirement, if he
wants to save money for retirement, then for retirement
itself we have three or four ways to
save money, so you understand that every
person, that is, the company understands the fact
that every person's condition is not the same,
his financial condition is not the same,
his way of saving, his
way of saving or his way of spending is not the same,
hence his way of investing is also
different, so one of us had many
criteria, that is, we were running the agency, which company was the most focused on
which war, that is, in all
three agencies, in life insurance,
hotel and health insurance, it was that
which company pays the most attention to the customer, so
motor insurance and health insurance
are small topics, I will explain them lightly to
you later,
but life insurance is available in three ways in life,
life insurance.  Your
life insurance is basically traditional
viewer policies, which means
child policies and investment policies, through which you
save money and make money.
I will tell you about these by
giving examples of two or three policies.
Okay, so let's start. So friends, the
name of this policy I am talking about is
SBI Life Smart Scholar. This is how we
save for our children's higher education, that is, for
college fees. You must be aware of
how much college fees are
rising these days, and you won't want money to come in the way of your child's dreams.
Obviously, if your child is
under 12 years old, you can take this policy. To
tell you the truth, there are
many people who, when their child is
not even a year old, they
take a health policy.
So why is this so? This is our second-best
selling policy, which is the best
selling
policy.
I will tell you why this is so. You will know for yourself
when you know its features. Okay,
what is in this policy?  This is because it is
for the education of children, so you have to deposit money till
your child turns 18.
Okay, now what
happens is that most of the colleges and these were of
304 years, now most of them have been made of 4 years,
first of all like your hotel
management etc. which was of 3 years, that also means it has become of 4
years, the rest of the
technical courses like engineering etc. are of 14 years only and if I
talk about MBBS etc. they are of 5 years
and on top of that they cost a lot,
that is okay and if I tell you in today's date itself, then the
money is increasing every year,
you must have seen last year's
strike also in Vidhi Medical College, so now
you think that if you have a baby today, then
after 18 years, he will be of
2018 years and will be
capable of writing on Facebook, so it will be
necessary for you to save for him, for the college fees,
now it is our human nature, it is the
nature of human being that when money  Once you get a
person, suppose you have taken a
policy of 10 lakhs or you have got a policy of 10 lakhs,
you thought that 10 lakhs will be enough for
my child's education,
okay, so if you have given
10 lakhs before this at the age of 18, you have deposited his fees in the first year,
lady Ruby, okay, now you
have seven and a half lakh rupees left, suppose you got some
work in between, one
year in between, now the next number is also to be given, so
what are you saying, come on friend, for now
I will give you this money along with it and
you have given a master of fifty thousand rupees,
so in this we do not do this, in this we
give you the policy in four parts,
maturity means when your child is 18 years old, then
19 years old, 20 years old and 21 years old,
you will get your money in one part, that is,
if you are taking a 10 year policy,
then in 18, 19, 20 and 21, and along
with this policy you get a bonus, that is,
when the child is
21 years old  So, you will
get this bonus in the installment that you get. Okay,
now let me tell you its benefits.
Suppose anything happens to you,
from the next day of taking the policy till the next day,
anything happens, then the first thing the bank will do is to
give 10 lakh rupees directly to your family because
your child will be studying in school at that time,
he will need school money,
your expenses of tuition fees, extracurricular
activities will be covered to cover all this
because look at the policy, for the child's education,
first you will be given ₹1000000. The
second thing will be that whatever you had
dreamt for your child, that is
₹1000000, you will deposit it and he will get it in
whichever college he studies, the
bank will pay it for you,
or if God forbid, you die
in the first year or the second year, then
how will the
bank pay all the premiums in the future and your
policy will continue as you had
made the policy, for whatever amount you had taken the policy, for how many
years, that means how many  The years will be
decided, if you have a one year old
child then there will be a policy for 17 years, if you have a
12 year old child then it will be a good policy
because the policy can be done till the child turns 18 years old, so
these are its benefits, along with that there will be tax
benefit which you will get,
so you can take this, if in that one year
tax of 45% is asked, then
even if you take this for 10 years, if your child
is eight years old, then also
you will save Rs 4.5 lakh in tax,
if
you take this policy at the age of eight years, now
see, this is a little bit of the first policy, this thing, I
want to talk about the second policy, for that
I will tell in a separate video, that is a
very good policy and along with this,
see, the health insurance and the ones for our
vehicles are the same for every company, it
means you do
not have to pay any money, why, if there
is a hospital in the panel of the vehicle, if there is a
showroom in the panel, then you do not have to pay any money  You have to pay
and if it is not in your panel
like Health Mission Hospital
is not in your panel then you have to take PM,
you have to submit all the documents, Pearl etc.
and you have to say this, it is the same
in motor insurance also that
you have to take from
then the showroom gives you the
preserve or it comes in the last so you will know the
advantage of this in the next in it I will tell you about health insurance
and what ICICI has done in motor insurance, that is, it
is different once, from taking the policy to
claiming the policy, it has made everything so easy
and has changed so much so
a separate video is made for that, that is the
whole time which used to be very dangerous for us to take the policy
and to take the claim,
if it is not in our panel, which many
people would know day by day, their
vehicle sometimes gets damaged and
they do not have a spoon, they mean they have taken
insurance from such a place from where they are
not getting the specialty, then they would
know that they have to fill this form,
attach the documents, go to the office,
then the surveyor comes, now you are good  Even if
you take all the documents from us
in half an hour, they do
not start working on your vehicle until the surveyor
comes and the server takes a
day or two to come. At least your days become
better.
Ishwari, further I will talk
about this. ICICI has made one thing so easy that
you can do
everything yourself. How to make
changes, I will tell you in a separate video,
which will be
for Chief Yogi Motor Insurance. This will be
for health insurance and the policy will be of
State Bank of India, in
which you can
subscribe and get interest ranging from
245 to 50% and if you
take a policy for more than 12 years, then it increases at the rate of 53 percent,
from one-fourth percent to 53 percent,
that money keeps increasing, along with that,
interest prematurity means that when you
get the money, there is no tax on it,
so I will tell you about this policy
in the next video, so stay tuned to this channel,
thank you.